Guide to Danbury's Third Century Research Collection MS 058
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Danbury's Third Century Research Collection
1983-2013
Western Connecticut State University Archives and Special Collections
Devlin, William
Janick, Herbert F.
MS 058
189
7 Linear Feet, 6 boxes, digital audio interviews
Research materials for Herb Janick and William Devlin's book, Danbury's Third Century. Includes a running summary of Danbury events taken from the news times, interviews, student theses, and published materials for the period of ~1870-2011.
Related Materials
Collections which relate to this collection in the WCSU Archives include:
The Truman Warner Papers
The Danbury Preservation Trust Records
The Herb Janick Papers
The James Dyer Papers
Biographical / Historical
Herbert Janick, PhD and William Devlin are two WCSU affiliated historians and co-authors of "Danbury's Third Century: From Urban Status to Tri-Centennial". Founder of the Danbury Preservation Trust in 1979, Dr. Janick has been instrumental in raising historical awareness among public audiences. For nearly thirty years, Dr. Janick taught history at Western Connecticut State University until his retirement in 1998. As professor emeritus, Dr. Janick wrote "A People's University: The Centennial History of Western Connecticut State University" and continued teaching courses in urban history at WCSU until 2007. Shortly after, Dr. Janick was asked to help complete "Danbury's Third Century". Three local historians, Steven Collins, Truman Warner, and Clarice Oseicki, all passed away in succession while in the process of writing this book. Danbury's Tercentennial Commission members, Mary Ann Frede and Barbara Susnitzky, remained committed to see the completion and publication of this book. However, Dr. Janick would not take the project alone and recruited William Devlin to co-author the book. Devlin, an adjunct professor at WCSU and active member of the Danbury Preservation Trust, wrote "We Crown Them All", a comprehensive illustrated history Danbury.
Completed in 2013 and published by Western Connecticut State University, "Danbury's Third Century" covers Danbury's transition from the 19th century through its tri-centennial. Confronting and exploring the City's class and race issues, urban development and redevelopment, industry and labor, real estate, social upheaval, and salient issues during this period.
Access Restrictions
Open for research with some restrictions. Interviews are available upon request.
Arrangement
Collection divided into three series:
Janick's Research Materials
Devlin's Research Materials
Interviews
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by William Devlin and Herb Janick between August 2013 and March 2014.
Scope and Contents
Materials are grouped into series reflecting Janick and Devlin's research. Janick's materials are arranged by year and Devlin's by subject. In the course of compiling their book they conducted interviews and recorded them - mostly at the WCSU Archives. Approximately half of the interviews were conducted with both authors present.
Janick created a handwritten running summary of topics contained in the Danbury News/Evening News/News-Times; these topics have been reproduced partially in notes relating to those folders; these are found in Subseries: "News-Times summary." The notes being handwritten are at times difficult to read so some of the transcription may contain errors. The transcription is not verbatim what is contained in the notes but where possible people, places, and events are culled from the notes. Researchers should utilize the notes and refer to microfilms of the Danbury papers when utilizing this material.
Danbury (Conn.) -- History.; Research notes.; Clippings.; Danbury News.
- Janick's Research Materials, 57697
  - Miscellaneous subject research, 57859
    - A Brief Discription of Danbury, 1960s; 57836 (Box 2, Folder 30)
      General note
      Hatting, The New Danbury, Poverty and Human Relations, Planning and Growth, Cultural and Intellectual Leadership, Exisiting Facilities for Meeting Community Needs
    - All-American City, 1968-1969; 57845 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      National Municipal League
    - Bill Cruse and Frederick Adams, 1929-2009; 57846 (Box 2, Folder 19)
      Bill Cruse, Ken Hanna, Charter Oak Terrace-Rice Heights Health Center, NAACP, Dr. Frederick Adams,
    - Business and Economy, 1946-2008; 57852 (Box 2, Folder 9-10)
      News-Times article on Rold J. Thal, Danbury News-Times article on Draft of "Danbury Crowned Them All: The Rise and Fall of the Hatting Industry and Danbury, Connecticut", News-Times articles: Commerce Park, Republic Foil, Bard Parker, John W. Douglas, Danbury Rubber article
    - Committee of 1000, 1926-1997; 57848 (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
      Rabbi Jerome Malino, Citizens Committee on Education, Taxpayer's Association, 1945 School Survey, Ruth A. Haas, Danbury Teachers, Danbury School Buildings, John Larson, Fair City Foundation, Bill Goodman, June Goodman, Danbury School Building Program
    - Community Services, 1967; 57837 (Box 2, Folder 29)
      PL 89-329 Title I, Community Services and Continuing Education Programs, An Action Study To Improve Poverty Conditions in Danbury Connecticut Growing Out Of the Wilder Report, Danbury State College
    - Consolidation, 1905-1996; 57843 (Box 2, Folder 22-23)
      Danbury Charter Amendment, Town of Danbury, City of Danbury, J. Thayer Bowman, Thomas A. Keating, 1963 Chart of Danbury's Government, Steve Collins, Consolidation Flyers "Vote Yes", Phone bank instructions pro Referendum on Consolidation
    - Corporate Center Information, 2006; 57715 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Danbury Industrial Corporation, 1918-2002; 57849 (Box 2, Folder 15)
      Meeting of Stockholders, Leadership Program, Company Contacts, Danbury Chamber of Commerce, Danbury Rotary Club, Financial Statement
    - Danbury Industrial Study, 1952; 57840 (Box 2, Folder 26)
      Alton Parker Aldrich, Industrial Transition in a New England Community Danbury, Connecticut, Notes on Aldrich Report
    - Danbury News Times Articles, 1962; 57854 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      Danbury News Times articles, Merchants, Condemnation, Urban Rewnewals
    - Danbury News Times Commemorative Issues, 1983-2008; 57834 (Box OS 1, Folder *)
      125 Year City Anniversary Commemorative, Danbury Fair Mall, News-Times Centennial Edition, Danbury Tri-Centennial Issue
    - Danbury Preservation Trust Material, Undated; 57716 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Danbury Sports, 1908-1940; 57855 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      James Thompson, Football Program, Danbury Trojans, Brooklyn Dodgers
    - Hatting, 1893-1985; 57847 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      Dana Frank, 1893 - 94 Lockout, J. Moss Ives, Governor Woodruff, Jeremiah Scully Interview, Tom McNally Interview, George Thorne Interview, Connecticut Industrial Workers
    - Kenneth Hanna, 1987-1988; 57856 (Box 2, Folder 5)
      Kenneth Hanna Interview, Kenneth Hanna letters
    - Minority Issues, 1930-2009; 57858 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
      Africian American immigration, State Civil Rights Commission, Lionel Bascom Interview, Richard Arcoti Interview, Gene Eriquez Interview, Sam Hyman, The Danbury Tutorial Project Interview; 1960 and 1970 Census, News Times articles on race issues, Church Segregation, Public Housing, Connecticut Schools, Connecticut State Colleges, Commission on Civil Rights Compliance Report
    - Paul Steinmetz, 2007; 57835 (Box 2, Folder 31)
      Oral History Interview Transcript, Paul Steinmetz
    - People, 2008-2011; 57838 (Box 2, Folder 28)
      Danbury News Times articles, U.S. Representitive William Ratchford, Dr. Nilo Herrera
    - Printed Material, ca.1920-1960; 57841 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      1960 Town of Danbury Plan of Development, 1948 Rediscovering Connecticut, circa 1920 Danbury Brochure
    - Post Flood Redevelopment Project, 1958-1964; 57853 (Box 2, Folder 8)
      News-Times Articles, Pat Heslin, Central Flood Urban Renewal Project (Final Project Report), Center East General Neighborhood Plan, Maps of Center East General Neighborhood Renewal Plan
    - Research Material and email, 2012; 57718 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Student Thesis, Edwin Benedict, 1632-1926; 57850 (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
      Edwin Benedict, The Felt-Hat Industry in the United States
    - Student Thesis, Raymond Rapp, 1946-1965; 57851 (Box 2, Folder 11-12)
      Raymond C. Rapp, The Growth of the Town of Danbury From 1949 - 1965 Under the Administration of Joesph H. Sauer
    - Student Thesis, Raymond J. Trimpert, 1969; 57839 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      Raymond J. Trimpert, A Study of Danbury's Industrial Transition, Notes on Thesis from Herbert Janick
    - The First Greek Immigrants in Lowell Massachussetts, Undated; 57717 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Urban Renewal, 1956-1990; 57857 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
      Urban Renewal Plan, Mid-Town East Neighborhood Development Program, Redevelopment Agency Effect on Still River
    - Urban Renewal Part I, 1911-1996; 57844 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      Jerry Lombard, State Highway, Housing Act of 1954, 1955 Flood, Interstate Highway, Still River
    - Wilder Report, 1966; 57842 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      David Wilder, Bureau of Applied Social Research, Final Report "An Assessment of the Community Needs of Danbury, CT and the Potential Role of Danbury State College in Community Service"
    - Compact Disc of Miscellaneous Computer Files Related to the Project, ca. 2008 (Box 6)
  - News-Times summary, 57860
    - Research Notes, 1870-1879, 57789 (Box 1, Folder 4.1)
      Scope and Contents
      Jan 6, 1870 Temperance meeting
      Jan 13, 1870 Pahquioque National Bank; Borough Hall meeting; John W. Bacon; Temperance; Edward Cody
      Jan 20, 1870 Fire Department; D. Ives Bushnell resigns; Registrars report
      Feb 17, 1870 Temperance order; Democratic Convention
      Mar 3, 1870 Highest tax payers; Henry Crofut; Alexander White; Edgar S. Tweedy; Tweedy and Company
      Mar 17, 1870 Merge of Danbury Times; Jeffersonian
      Mar 24, 1870 Centre School District Meeting; Power of principle; Expel students
      Apr 5, 1870 Election results; Danbury Trust Company
      Apr 14, 1870 J.S. Taylor; Excessive discipline; Harsh school rules; Centre School; Flood; St. Peters Church; George Bailey; Letters to J.S. Taylor; Excessive discipline at Centre School; Women teachers
      Apr 21, 1870 Centre School; Support of principle; District school committee; A.T. Pech; E.A. Malloy; J. Ausbury; school district; 850 children; expenses
      Apr 28, 1870 Public meeting; W.L. Hayden; school solution; harsh discipline; educational tools
      May 5, 1870 Col. N.L. White
      May 12, 1870 Jeffersonian school budget
      May 26, 1870 Danbury hotels; E.D. Ritton
      Jun 2, 1870 Discription of Memorial Day; Meeting at St. Peter's Church
      Jun 9, 1870 Guthers furniture
      Jun 16, 1870 Real Estate
      Jun 23, 1870 Borough election; Oliver P. Clark
      Aug 4, 1870 Election of St. Peter Cathedral
      Sept 15, 1870 Bartram & Fantom Sewing Machine Co.; General James Ryder
      Sept 22, 1870 Public Library; Edgar S. Tweedy; WM A. White
      Oct 13, 1870 Danbury Farmers; Manufacturers
      Oct 20, 1870 building school
      Oct 27, 1870 Colored people of Danbury; Sherman Guard; James Wallace Pine
      Nov 3, 1870 Conditions at Alms House
      Dec 7, 1870 Library
      Dec 21, 1870 Article on Centre District School
      Jan 11, 1871 Hartford Post; Bartram & Fantom Sewing Machine Co.
      Jan 18, 1871 Democratic Caucus
      Jan 25, 1871 School of Libery Street
      Feb 1, 1871 Death of John Risler; Danbury Norwalk Railraod
      Feb 15, 1871 German immigration; church location editorial; Bethel deaths 1823-32
      Feb 22, 1871 temperance meeting; description of solution in Danbury
      Mar 1, 1871 Silk hats
      Mar 8, 1871 George Beers; E. S. Tweedy letter
      Mar 15, 1871 Bethel death
      Mar 22, 1871 Temperance; Need to pave Main St; Boot & Shoe Co.
      Apr 5, 1871 Express Train; Henry N. Fanton; Edwin R. Humiston; Election; *HJ
      Apr 12, 1871 effort to arrange temperance movement; support to old Washington's movement; Danbury Temperance Association
      Apr 19, 1871 Danbury temperance arranged; organization of temperance; Washington Total Abstinence Society; temperance reform article
      Apr 26, 1871 2nd temperance meeting; Danbury description of Main St. (east side); West to White St.
      May 3, 1871 Description of west Main St.; 3rd temperance meeting
      May 10, 1871 description of caucus; Temperance; Washington Monument?
      May 17, 1871 Temperance
      May 24, 1871 street improvements; expenses; Concert HallTemperance
      May 31, 1871 Decaration Day; Hat (Fur & Wool); Temperance
      Jun 7, 1871 Benedict Brom (Boots & Shoes Dealer); Dr. E.P. Bennett; White Street
      Jun 21, 1871 E.P. Bennett from A.T.P.
      Jun 28, 1871 new opera
      Jul 5, 1871 West St
      Jul 12, 1871 E.Sowdy
      Jul 19, 1871 temperance meeting
      Jul 26, 1871 St. Peter's Church; Journeyman; Hat trade
      Aug 2, 1871 temperance meeting; letter from "an old hatter"
      Aug 9, 1871 meeting of voters of Centre School Dist.; Town meeting; debate on Civil War movement
      Aug 16, 1871 Center of education in Danbury
      Aug 23, 1871 G. White
      Aug 30, 1871 New York for Danbury; E. S. Tweedy; D.P. Nichols; John W. Bacon; W.P. Sealy
      Sept 6, 1871 Report of meeting by committee
      Sept 13, 1871 debate of management on Batram & Fanton
      Sept 27, 1871 New company-Danbury stores
      Oct 4, 1871 Election of town offices; temperance
      Oct 11, 1871 town meeting
      Oct 18, 1871 temperence
      Oct 25, 1871 New York border
      Nov 1, 1871 Temperance
      Nov 8, 1871 Temperance parade
      Nov 22, 1871 temperance
      Dec 20, 1871 opening of Shepaug Railroad
      Jan 10, 1872 article on Shepaug R.R.
      Jan 17, 1872 coal trade
      Jan 24, 1872 Bartram & Fanton Co. new journeymen
      Feb 7, 1872 E.P. Bennett; free public
      Feb 14, 1872 E. F. Harden
      Feb 21, 1872 E.P. Bennett in school; Wooster Home description
      Mar 13, 1872 E.F. Harden in Dr. Bennett's school
      May 8, 1872 Bartram & fanton Sewing Co.
      Aug 21, 1872 meeting on Wooster Home
      Oct 9, 1872 Election
      Oct 28, 1872 A.T. Peck; E. S. Tweedy
      Nov 6, 1872 election
      Jan 1, 1873 Editorial size of paper
      Jan 15, 1873 6th annual farmers convention in Danbury; directors of Danbury Hall
      Jan 22, 1873 13 buses of workers to Danbury
      Jan 29, 1873 registers report
      Feb 5, 1873 Rep. delegates selected
      Feb 12, 1873 meeting of Washington; article on future of Bartram & Fanton Co.; new building of company
      Feb 19, 1873 Democratic delegates
      Mar 18, 1873 Temperance meeting
      Apr 2, 1873 meeting of Danbury offices; women faculty
      Apr 9, 1873 Dr. Willihan
      May 14, 1873 death of Charles T. Stevens
      Jun 4, 1873 meeting of Washington
      Jun 15, 1873 Crosby & Nichols
      Aug 27, 1873 Father Mathews Young; Young Mans Temperance Society
      Sept 3, 1873 Fire at Sturdevant's Hat Factory; Peter Barnum obituary
      Sept 10, 1873 renunion of 23rd regement
      Sept 17, 1873 one of the boys letter Young Mans Temperance Society
      Oct 15, 1873 First ball of Hibernians
      Nov 12, 1873 Samiritan lodge of "I.O.O.F."
      Dec 3, 1873 Danbury library
      Dec 31, 1873 Borough meeting
      Jan 7, 1874 St. Vincent's
      Jan 14, 1874 description of floods; 2 letters on temperance
      Feb 4, 1874 Samuel Stebbins; list of arrests
      Feb 11, 1874 Republican caucus
      Feb 18, 1874 Taylor
      Feb 25, 1874 Borough meeting; inspection of building
      Mar 4, 1874 Danbury Savings Bank; West St. side walk; Sturdevant's Hat Factory; Republican Caucus; Col. Adkins; G.D. Foote; E.H. Taylor; William P. Seely
      Mar 25, 1874 Masquerade ball; Edmond Tweedy; Relief Society
      Apr 1, 1874 Republican caucus; Democratic Caucus
      Apr 8, 1874 Isabella Beecher Hooker; suffrage; election results; Reverend Alpheus Winter
      Apr 15, 1874 Plants Spring Opening
      Apr 22, 1874 3rd annual Jubelee
      May 6, 1874 Gas street lamps
      May 13, 1874 Gas street lamps
      May 27, 1874 hotel
      Jun 3, 1874 Aetna Baseball Club; Decoration Day
      Jun 10, 1874 meeting of Bartram & Fanton Sewing Co.
      Jun 17, 1874 Bartram & Fanton
      Jul 1, 1874 Borough Election
      Jul 15, 1874 Union Savings Bank
      Jul 24, 1874 Bartram & Fanton Co.
      Aug 5, 1874 Poor house
      Aug 19, 1874 LN
      Sept 16, 1874 Thomas Taylor
      Sept 23, 1874 Saint Peter's Church
      Sept 30, 1874 town election
      Oct 28, 1874 New Water House
      Nov 4, 1874 Stockholders of Danbury & Norwalk Railroad
      Nov 11, 1874 Connelly call "Tramp"
      Nov 18, 1874 9th fire since July 4
      Dec 16, 1874 Prohibition Convention
      Jan 6, 1875 New buildings; W.W. Sunderland
      Jan 13, 1875 W.A. & A.M. White Factory; fire
      Jan 20, 1875 births & deaths of 1874
      Feb 3, 1875 ST. James Episcopal Church; temperance meeting; Saint Peter's church
      Feb 10, 1875 New Street School
      Feb 17, 1875 Merritt & Sprague; police editorial
      Feb 24, 1875 Poor farm; coal shortage; Saint Ives School
      Mar 3, 1875 Saint Ives School; eight robberies one night; Main Street; Borough meeting
      Mar 10, 1875 Saint Ives; Prohibition Convention
      Mar 17, 1875 Danbury and Old Times; Saint Ives; Saint Patrick's Day; police
      Mar 24, 1875 Old Danbury; E. Hoyt
      Mar 31, 1875 Coal scare; building prospects; Democrats & Republicans
      Apr 7, 1875 Danbury and Old Times
      Apr 14, 1875 E. Hoyt
      Apr 21, 1875 Danbury Grange
      Apr 28, 1875 Buddy notes
      May 5, 1875 Borough election
      May 12, 1875 Borough election
      May 19, 1875 Lowenburgh Brothers; building notes
      May 26, 1875 Comb workers; A.T.P.; library books
      Jun 2, 1875 Comb workers
      Jun 9, 1875 Comb workers
      Jun 16, 1875 Danbury Norwalk Railroad
      Jun 30, 1875 S.C. Rundle house
      Jul 7, 1875 People of color; school assessments
      Jul 21, 1875 police
      Aug 4, 1875 police; By-laws of Borough Danbury
      Aug 25, 1875 Flooding
      Sept 1, 1875 Harvey & Levy Osborne; 10 year retrospective
      Sept 29, 1875 Catholic Church
      Oct 6, 1875 elections
      Nov 3, 1875 Lake Kohanza
      Nov 17, 1875 Real estate transfers
      Dec 15, 1875 dedications of Saint Peter's
      Dec 29, 1875 Fire department truck
      Jan 5, 1876 Edward Tweedy
      Jan 12, 1876 Opera House
      Feb 2, 1876 Saloon's of Danbury
      Feb 9, 1876 Schools
      Feb 16, 1876 Baptist Church
      Mar 1, 1876 Revival meeting
      Mar 29, 1876 Democrats & Republicans
      Apr 5, 1876 elections
      Apr 19, 1876 P.T. Barnum; centennial
      May 3, 1876 Borough elections
      May 10, 1876 Danbury legislatures; Women assaulted
      Jun 28, 1876 Danbury Bible Society; Juvenile deliquents
      Jul 5, 1876 Centennial; History of Danbury
      Jul 12, 1876 Danbury School report; Mayor
      Jul 19, 1876 Fire department
      Jul 26, 1876 Police
      Aug 2, 1876 Letter on hatting; Too many hatters
      Aug 9, 1876 Letter on hatting response
      Aug 30, 1876 17th Regiment reunion; Increase in hat manufacturing
      Oct 4, 1876 Town meeting
      Nov 1, 1876 Democrats & Republicans; Twighlight parade; Turner Hats
      Nov 8, 1876 Elections
      Nov 22, 1876 Col. Nelson L. White; E. Moss White
      Dec 6, 1876 H. Crofut; Drunken party
      Dec 13, 1876 Letters from Prof. Hernon?
      Dec 20, 1876 Town meeting
      Jan 3, 1877 Moose Lodge; Town Meeting; Crofut
      Jan 10, 1877 Area Legislators
      Jan 17, 1877 Col. Nelson L. White
      Jan, 1877 Hat Furriers Trade
      Feb 21, 1877 Danbury and Norwalk Railroad; Hats and Boots
      Mar 7, 1877 Danbury Retail
      Mar 14, 1877 Young Hoodlums
      Mar 21, 1877 Attack on Main St
      Apr 4, 1877 School Report
      Apr 11, 1877 Real Estate
      Apr 18, 1877 Library; Hats and Boots
      May 2, 1877 Bonfires
      May 16, 1877 Borough Election
      Jun 6, 1877 Fire
      Jun 20, 1877 Wm P. Cosmoteet; Edgar Jefferson Patret; Manufactured Goods
      Jul 5, 1877 School Report
      Jul 11, 1877 Real Estate
      Jul, 1877 Col. Nelson L. White; Yale
      Jul 18, 1877 Library
      Jul 25, 1877 Riot; Turner Street
      Aug 1, 1877 Mill Plain
      Aug 8, 1877 Main Street; Colored Persons; Streeet Lights
      Aug 22, 1877 WCTU Gospel; County Jail
      Aug 15, 1877 Burglaries; Crofut, White, and Peabody
      Aug 29, 1877 W.J. Humphreys; W.A. White; G.M. Rundle; E.P. Bennett; A.M. Rundle
      Sep 5, 1877 E.P. Bennett; Police; City Government
      Sep 12, 1877 E.P. Bennett; Courts; Tax Payers; Center School District; Elections; Fire at Tweedy and Hoyt Hat Shop
      Sep 19, 1877 Town Meeting; Gray & Holly Milliners; Crofuts block; V.E. Barnum; Colored people; Concert Hall; Judge Peters
      Sep 26, 1877 Furriers; Hull and Rogers; Ives and Hoyt; Andrews and Parsons; Saloons; Hall and Belden; Mesret and Cone; Prominent fires
      Sep 31, 1877 Republician; Democrat; J.H. Folson
      Nov 7, 1877 Election; E.S. Davis and Company; E.S. Davis; Charles Hull; Henry Crofut; Anwley and Company; F.A. Austin; Becherlice and Company; Real Estate
      Nov 14, 1877 Charles Doren
      Nov 21, 1877 Total Abstinence Society
      Dec 5, 1877 Hebrew Wedding; Morris Cohn; Fannie Harris; Town Meeting
      Dec 12, 1877 A. Abbotts
      Dec 19, 1877 Telephone; Tweedy Mfg. Company
      Dec 26, 1877 Monuments; Cemetary
      Jan 2, 1878 Meekers Hat Factory; Douglas Feroslot
      Jan 9, 1878 Directory
      Jan 23, 1878 Arnold Selesters
      Jan 30, 1878 Tweedy
      Feb 27, 1878 Old Concert Hall
      Mar 6, 1878 Concert Hall; Danbury Ice
      Mar 13, 1878 Temperance
      Mar 20, 1878 Temperance
      Mar 27, 1878 Water Supply
      Apr 3, 1878 Temperance
      Apr 10, 1878 Temperance
      Apr 17, 1878 Temperance
      Apr 24, 1878 Temperance; Old Concert Hall
      May 8, 1878 Burglaries
      May 15, 1878 Borough Courts; Election
      May 22, 1878 Foster Borthers
      May 29, 1878 Temperance; E.A. Armerson
      Jun 19, 1878 Meeker Brothers; Hat Factory
      Jul 10, 1878 Soldiers Monument
      Sep 12, 1878 Elections; Fire at Tweedy and Hoyt Hat Shop
      Sep 19, 1878 Gray & Holly Milliners; Crofuts block; V.E. Barnum; Colored people; Concert Hall; Judge Peters
      Sep 26, 1878 Prominent fires
      Aug 21, 1878 Soldiers Cemetary
      Aug 28, 1878 Vox; Concert Hall; Monument
      Sep 11, 1878 Parade
      Sep 18, 1878 Democratic Caucus; Democratic State Convention
      Sep 25, 1878 Temperance; Monument
      Oct 9, 1878 Elections
      Oct 16, 1878 Temperance
      Oct 30, 1878 Monument Society
      Nov 6, 1878 Elections
      Nov 13, 1878 Library Building; John H. Benedict; Ives and Hoyt
      Nov 20, 1878 AME Zion Church; Baptist Church
      Dec 4, 1878 Burglaries
      Dec 11, 1878 Temperance; Randall and Bradley Grocery
    - Research Notes, 1881-1886, 57790 (Box 1, Folder 4.2)
      Jan 5, 1881 Review of important events of 1880
      Jan 13, 1881 Farmers Club
      Jan 19, 1881 State legislatures
      Jan 26, 1881 Consensus of Centre School District
      Feb 2, 1881 Students of school centre
      Feb 8, 1881 Hat shipment; NY & NE RR
      Feb 9, 1881 Meeting of Reform Association; Young New Temperance Association; Cadets of Honor & Temperance; Temperance Reform Association Campaign
      Mar 14, 1881 Borough meeting
      Mar 30, 1881 White & Porter
      Apr 1, 1881 Bartram
      Apr 6, 1881 Franklin Street; G. Hoyt; L.P. Hoyt; A.N. Wildman; E. Tweedy
      Apr 13, 1881 Bridgeport; Foot & Shoe
      Apr 20, 1881 Col. Moss White; Folsom Temperance Reform Assoc.
      Apr 27, 1881 Borough meeting
      May 4, 1881 New Hat Company
      May 10, 1881 Borough election